<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <atom:link href="https://enindu.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <title>Enindu Alahapperuma</title>
        <link>https://enindu.com</link>
        <image>
            <url>https://enindu.com/images/rss.png</url>
            <title>Enindu Alahapperuma</title>
            <link>https://enindu.com</link>
        </image>
        <description><![CDATA[Besides offering back-end development and system administration services, I also write articles in my spare time. These articles mainly focus on web development, software I've created, and my personal insights on various topics.]]></description>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2025 23:29:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[I Have Revamped My Website]]></title>
            <link>https://enindu.com/blog/i-have-revamped-my-website</link>
            <description><![CDATA[I have upgraded the Laravel framework to version 12, made significant improvements to the front-end design, and added service pages to the website. This means I am now officially offering my services as a freelancer. Read below to learn more about these updates.]]></description>
            <author>enindu@gmail.com (Enindu Alahapperuma)</author>
            <guid>https://enindu.com/1</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2025 23:29:00 +0530</pubDate>
            <category>General</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ultimate Web Development Guide For Clients]]></title>
            <link>https://enindu.com/blog/ultimate-web-development-guide-for-clients</link>
            <description><![CDATA[I come across numerous web development groups on Facebook every day. These groups are filled with people—some searching for web developers at low prices, while others are offering their services for equally low rates. This obsession with cheap work has distorted the true value of web development in recent years. The reality is, web development is not cheap at all.]]></description>
            <author>enindu@gmail.com (Enindu Alahapperuma)</author>
            <guid>https://enindu.com/2</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 19:40:00 +0530</pubDate>
            <category>General</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Understanding HTTP]]></title>
            <link>https://enindu.com/blog/understanding-http</link>
            <description><![CDATA[There are countless articles and videos on the internet explaining what HTTP is. If I were to write this post in the same way, it would just be another one among many. Instead, I'll be breaking down HTTP from the perspective of a back-end engineer, highlighting common issues developers face with it. Let's dive in.]]></description>
            <author>enindu@gmail.com (Enindu Alahapperuma)</author>
            <guid>https://enindu.com/3</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 08 Mar 2025 15:55:00 +0530</pubDate>
            <category>General</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Playing With HTTP Servers]]></title>
            <link>https://enindu.com/blog/playing-with-http-servers</link>
            <description><![CDATA[In a previous article, I provided a high-level overview of HTTP. In this article, I will dive into the low-level implementation of HTTP, covering topics such as creating HTTP servers and even lower-level TCP servers. Discussions on HTTP and TCP clients will be reserved for a separate article. Expect plenty of code examples. So, let's get started.]]></description>
            <author>enindu@gmail.com (Enindu Alahapperuma)</author>
            <guid>https://enindu.com/4</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 09 Mar 2025 11:44:00 +0530</pubDate>
            <category>General</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Shared Hosting Explained For Clients]]></title>
            <link>https://enindu.com/blog/shared-hosting-explained-for-clients</link>
            <description><![CDATA[This isn't just another article explaining shared hosting. Instead, I'll break it down from a system administrator's perspective—why you should never use shared hosting, even for a small web application, and what better alternatives exist. If you're looking for affordable hosting solutions, this will be a comprehensive guide, much like my previous article on web development. Let's dive in!]]></description>
            <author>enindu@gmail.com (Enindu Alahapperuma)</author>
            <guid>https://enindu.com/5</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 12:01:00 +0530</pubDate>
            <category>General</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Understanding DNS]]></title>
            <link>https://enindu.com/blog/understanding-dns</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Most developers have a high-level understanding of DNS. However, for web developers, grasping DNS at a low level is crucial. Writing yet another article explaining DNS from a high-level perspective would be redundant. Instead, this article delves into the DNS protocol and its inner workings at a low level, offering a system administrator's perspective. Let's dive in.]]></description>
            <author>enindu@gmail.com (Enindu Alahapperuma)</author>
            <guid>https://enindu.com/6</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2025 01:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
            <category>General</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Playing With DNS Clients]]></title>
            <link>https://enindu.com/blog/playing-with-dns-clients</link>
            <description><![CDATA[In a previous article, I provided a low-level overview of DNS servers. While it wasn't an exhaustive guide, it covered the fundamentals to help you understand how DNS works. In this article, I'll build on that foundation with real-world examples. Let's dive in!]]></description>
            <author>enindu@gmail.com (Enindu Alahapperuma)</author>
            <guid>https://enindu.com/7</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 21:32:00 +0530</pubDate>
            <category>General</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Running Shell Commands Within Shared Hosting]]></title>
            <link>https://enindu.com/blog/running-shell-commands-within-shared-hosting</link>
            <description><![CDATA[In a previous article, I discussed shared hosting. In this one, I'll be experimenting with a shared hosting server. My goal is to highlight a vulnerability and help you approach certain aspects from a different perspective. Let's get started!]]></description>
            <author>enindu@gmail.com (Enindu Alahapperuma)</author>
            <guid>https://enindu.com/8</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 15:20:00 +0530</pubDate>
            <category>General</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How Poor Development Skills Break Internet]]></title>
            <link>https://enindu.com/blog/how-poor-development-skills-break-internet</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The most important part of a website's lifecycle is probably the development skills, with infrastructure skills coming second. I often come across websites built with poor development practices that are easy to hack. Seeing this so often has frustrated me and inspired me to write this article. So without wasting any more time, let's get straight to the point.]]></description>
            <author>enindu@gmail.com (Enindu Alahapperuma)</author>
            <guid>https://enindu.com/9</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jul 2025 14:13:00 +0530</pubDate>
            <category>General</category>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
